Shonda Loyola

4153 Ames Blvd Marrero, La 70072 sloyolarnbsn@gmail.com 504-669-0117

Profile

Registered nurse with fourteen years of experience in many areas. Strong patient educator, advocate and liaison. Substantial knowledge base in assessment, implementation, and evaluation of patient care. Superb interpersonal skills. Excellent organizational skills, problem solving skills and time management. Works well with others in a team dynamic setting. Adaptable, flexible and capable of working independently. Mediator between physicians, ancillary staff, and patient's family.

Experience

Coordination of Care, Department of Veterans Affairs New Orleans, La 2013-present

Utilization Management--research cases for level of care appropriateness, handle multiple patient cases at a time, excellent time management skills, proficient computer skills, handle changes in direction well, establishes

positive relationships with peers and community liaisons. Collaborates across services and departments, with care coordinators, case managers, discharge planners, providers, nursing staff, patient flow coordinators, social workers, and transfer coordinators to ensure safe, quality, cost-effective transitional care. Conducts, analyzes and documents utilization management reviews consistent with national guidance, entering data into system. Reviews include pre-admission screening, admission reviews, continued stay reviews, and occurrence screening reviews. Participated in Administrative Investigational Boards.

Staff Registered Nurse, Tulane University Hospital and Clinics New Orleans, La 2006-Oct. 2013

PACU--Direct patient care of post-operative surgical patients. Charge nurse responsibilities and preceptor to new hires. Assesses patient status and notifies physician of changes. Administration and documentation of patient medication. Documentation of patient assessments and procedures performed. Educate patient and family regarding medication, wound assessment, dressing changes, and infection signs and symptoms. Maintain patient safety and privacy per HIPPA daily. Troubleshoots complications daily. Delegate duties appropriately as necessary. Assist with admission and discharge of patients. Perform clinical tasks per hospital policy daily. Establish positive relationship with peers and patients.

Abdominal Transplant Unit/ICU--Direct patient care of both critical care and medical-surgical patients daily. Administration and documentation of transplant rejection drugs daily. Assesses patient status and notifies physician of changes. Administration and documentation of patient medication. Documentation of patient assessments and procedures performed. Educate patient and family regarding medication, wound assessment, dressing changes, and infection signs and symptoms. Maintain patient safety and privacy per HIPPA daily. Troubleshoots complications daily. Delegate duties appropriately as necessary. Assist with admission and discharge of patients. Perform clinical tasks per hospital policy daily. Establish positive relationship with peers and patients.

Staff Registered Nurse, West Jefferson Medical Center Marrero, La 2000-2006

5 South--Direct patient care of medical-surgical patients specializing in orthopedic/neurological. Charge nurse responsibilities and preceptor to new hires. Assesses patient status and notifies physician of changes. Administration and documentation of patient medication. Documentation of patient assessments and procedures performed. Educate patient and family regarding medication, wound assessment, dressing changes, and infection signs and symptoms. Maintain patient safety and privacy per HIPPA daily. Troubleshoots complications daily. Delegate duties appropriately as necessary. Assist with admission and discharge of patients. Perform clinical tasks per hospital policy daily. Establish positive relationship with peers and patients. Application of and removal of skin traction. Review charts and care plans daily.

Circulation Clerk, Times Picayune New Orleans, La 1994-1997

Customer retention. Resolved customer complaints. Trained new hires. Handles customer financial needs. Computer knowledgeable (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Education

Loyola University New Orleans, La—Bachelor of Science in Nursing 2009
Charity School of Nursing New Orleans, La—Associate of Science in Nursing 2004
Nunez Community College Chalmette, La—Licensed Practical Nursing degree 1999
University of Louisiana at Lafavette—Nursing prerequisites 1993-1997

Referrals

Gina Bloodsworth, RN (504) 251-3358 Ericha Champagne, RN BSN (504) 650-7729 Lavonne Paul, RN BSN (504) 450-9472